KRISNA GUPTA

PhD Candidate in Economics at The Australian National University (ANU)

At Crawford School of Public policy under supervision of Arianto Patunru. My thesis is about the impact of trade and investment policies to Indonesian firms. I am a full time lecturer at Politeknik APP Jakarta, part time lecturer at Universitas Indonesia, and an associate researcher at CIPS Indonesia.



EDUCATION

2014 Universitas Indonesia
M.S.E. in Economics

Depok, Indonesia

• VU University Amsterdam

CONTACT INFO

krisna.or.id

For more information, please contact me via email.

SELECTED RESEARCH AND PUBLICATIONS

Book

2014

 Gupta, Krisna and Enny Mardjono (2021). Indonesia Emas Berkelanjutan 2045: Kumpulan Pemikiran Pelajar Indonesia Sedunia Seri 01 Ekonomi. Jakarta: LIPI Press. ISBN: 978-602-496-208-1

Journal Article

- Gupta, Krisna. (2022). The Heterogenous Impact of Tariff and NTM on Total Factor Productivity of Indonesian Firms. *Bulletin of Indonesian Economic Studies*. DOI: 10.1080/00074918.2021.2016613
- Gupta, Krisna. (2021). The Importance of Financial Liberalisation for Economic Growth: The Case of Indonesia. *Bulletin of Indonesian Economic Studies*, 57:2, 175-201, DOI: 10.1080/00074918.2020.1747596

Book Chapter

• Gupta, Krisna. (2020). "Industri 4.0 Sebagai Solusi Daya Saing Industri Indonesia?". In Denny Irawan, Wasisto Raharjo Jati, Oscar Karnalim, Asrul Sidiq (ed.), *Mewujudkan Indonesia 4.0: Kumpulan Pemikiran Pelajar Indonesia di Australia*. Jakarta: Yayasan Pustaka Obor Indonesia. ISBN: 978-602-433-918-0

Policy Paper

• Gupta, Krisna, Deasy Pane and Donny Pasaribu. (2022). "The advent of a new trade governance after the Omnibus Law: Neraca Komoditas". *CIPS Policy Paper* no.47.

Book Review

 Gupta, Krisna. (2020). "World Trade Evolution: Growth, Productivity and Employment - edited by Lili Yan Ing and Miaojie Yu". Asian-Pacific Economic Literature. https://doi.org/DOI:10.1111/apel.12291

SKILLS

Trained in economics with heavy use of various types of panel data regressions to evaluate policies

Have a long exposure with Stata, R, and Python for data analytics and econometrics

Experience in running structural model (e.g. GTAP) with GEMPACK software

Good familiarity with various data & docs processing tools (Microsoft Office, Google Docs, Rstudio & $\angle T_F X$)

This resume was made with the R package **pagedown**.

Last updated on 2022-07-31.

Popular Publications / Oped

- Gupta, Krisna and Deasy Pane. 2021. "Restrictive regulations on foreign trade may hurt economy". The Jakarta Post.
- Pasaribu, Donny and Krisna Gupta. 2020. "Will IA-CEPA be the boost to Australia-Indonesia relations leaders are banking on?". Indonesia At Melbourne.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Lecturer

- Politeknik APP (home institution): Business Statistics (2016-2017)
- Universitas Petra: Intro to Economics (2020)

Tutor at Australian National University

- POLS3025 Contemporary Political Analysis, using Stata in political analyses (2017)
- ECON3101 Microeconomics 3 (2018-2021)
- ECON3102 Macroeconomics 3 (2021)
- EMET3008 Applied Macro and Financial Econometrics (2020)

I CONSULTING EXPERIENCE

Economist 2020

Center for Indonesian Policy Studies

♀ Jakarta, Indonesia

- Design a policy evaluation method CGE and Stata is used. on IACEPA implementation for Prospera.

 - · Work under Reiner Heufers.

Economist 2020

PT. LAPI ITB.

Jakarta, Indonesia

- Run a simulation to assess the impact of Indonesian Sovereign Wealthh Fund.
- · Mainly use Computable General Equilibrium (CGE).
- · Work under Dr. Barli Suryanta.

PRIZES

VU Fellowship Programme (VUFP) 2012

A scholarship given by VU for my master degree

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Australia Awards Indonesia (AAI) 2017

A scholarship from the Australian government to conduct a study in Australia.

Canberra, Australia

Hadi Soesastro Prize (HSP) 2019

> Awarded by the Australian government to be used for research in Indonesian development

> > Canberra, Australia